

SUMUKH VASISHT S

Address:

1436/1, 6th Cross, Krishnamurthy Puram, Mysore-570004

Phone:

+91 8880478748

Email:

sumukhmys1999@gmail.com

Github:

www.github.com/sumukh-vasisht

Website:

https://svs.codes/

LinkedIn:

https://in.linkedin.com/in/sumukh -vasisht-s-2814a8186

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Creative design
- Team Player

Technical Skills

Data Science:

Matplotlib Seaborn
Plotly mpld3
Apache Spark Hadoop
SQL MongoDB

Statistics

Programming:

C C++
Python JavaScript
HTML/CSS Vue.Js

Tools and Technologies:

Github

Summary

Information Science and Engineering student, specializing in Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Full stack development and web application development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects and data science and analytics.

Education

Engineering:

The National Institute of Engineering, Mysore Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science

Anticipated Graduation: June 2021 CGPA: 9.02/10.0 (Six Semesters)

PUC(2015-2017):

Marimmallappa's PU College, Mysore

Percentage: 94.5% (2nd PUC) **10th Standard**(2014-15): V.V.S.B.M.Sri E.I, Mysore

CGPA: 10.0/10.0

Experience

Al Engineer - 08/2020 to Present

Research Intern - 02/2020 to 07/2020

Antriksh Labs Pvt. Ltd., Mysore

Currently working as an AI Engineer at Antriksh Labs, Mysore, where I'm contributing towards the development of Data Visualization Pipeline and Statistical analysis. Using technologies and languages like Python, Spark, Hadoop, SQL, etc. Sumedh S Vijay, CEO & Co-Founder, Antriksh Labs Pvt. Ltd.

Email ID: sumedh@antrikshlabs.space **Software Intern** - 03/2019 to 10/2019

Deshik Labs, Mysore

Completed an eight month internship at Deshik Labs, Mysore, where I was contributing to the development of PWAs and websites for different clients, which involved work right from meeting the clients, all through development and testing.

Shreesha Ramaswamy, Founder, Deshik Labs

Email ID: shreesha@deshik.in

Projects

Data Visualization an Statistics Computation of Datasets

 Data Visualization Pipeline (March 2020 – Present)
 The pipeline involves data cleaning, computing statistics,
 Visualizing the dataset by various kinds of plots through matplotlib, seaborn, mpld3, e-charts, etc., implementing different ML models on the dataset and Exploratory
 Data Analysis.

SUMUKH VASISHT S

Organizations

1. IEEE

Active IEEE member form the past 3 years.

 NIE IEEE Student Branch (Student Branch of IEEE at NIE)

> Coordinated with RPs for numerous workshops and tech talks. Coordinated Industrial Visits to CISCO and DELL EMC.

3. **U&I**

Working as an active volunteer at the NGO aimed at imparting quality education for underprivileged kids.

4. techNIEks'20

Volunteered as a convener for the website development team for our college fest in 2020.

Achievements

- Presented a paper and published an article at 'International Conference of Human-Wildlife Conflict Mitigation'
- 2. AIR 2 in RIE CEE
- 3. Lead a team and presented findings on 'Medicinal uses of soil' at National Children Science Congress.
- Won numerous prizes at state and national level quiz and debate contests.

- 2. Tweet Analyzer (April 2020): NLP based web app which scraps data off twitter and analyzes sentiments of the tweets including those of COVID-19. Built with HTML/CSS and Python tweepy, pandas, textblob, re (Link: www.github.com/sumukh-vasisht/twitterWeb)
- Self-Checkout System (March 2020 August 2020): IoT based self-checkout system for shopping centers. Built using Raspberry Pi, Python, Firebase, HTML/CSS and JavaScript.
- 4. Cric-Predicc (September 2019 October 2019)
 Data Analytics Project which predicts the winner of a cricket match. Coded using Python sklearn, keras.
 (Link: www.github.com/sumukh-vasisht/CricPredict)
- 5. VCast Foundry App (March 2019 July 2019) An operations and management application for a casting industry, called VCast in Mysore, built using Framework7 with Vue, VueJS, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Node.JS, Firebase and Firestore.
- 6. Tribal Tattoos Website (August 2019 October 2019) Website for a tattoo parlor in Mysore. Developed using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap for frontend and Python-Flask for the backend.

(Link: <u>www.tattoomysore.com</u>)

All my other projects can be found in my github repository

Certifications

- 1. Machine Learning: Stanford University
- 2. Neural Networks and Deep Learning: deeplearning.ai
- 3. Data Science using Python: Michigan University

Extra-Curricular Activities

- SAC Coordinator (June, 2019 July, 2020), Digital Design Lead and Student Branch Networking Coordinator (2018-19) at NIE IEEE Student Branch
- 2. Student Ambassador for IEEEXtreme 14.0
- 3. Part of the team which organized NIE Summer of Code 6.0.
- 4. Conducted various workshops and sessions on Machine Learning, Game Development, competitive coding, etc.
- 5. Hosted many inter colligate competitive coding competitions.
- 6. Conducted Focus Group Sessions on Web Development.
- 7. Pianist, guitarist and singer in the college band 'Swayam'.